让我们看看这个简单的例子。当你和我看到我们可以看到一个
Let’s look at this simple example. When you and I look at that we can see an
鲨鱼的形象。但就计算机视觉系统而言，它只是一个矩阵
image of the shark. But as far as a computer vision system is concerned, it is just a matrix
满满的数字。事实上，这500×500像素的图像包含25万个数字。
full of numbers. In fact this 500 by 500 pixel image contains a quarter of a million numbers.
但是看着这个人的人看到了一个独特的对象。所以挑战是我们如何找到
But human beings looking at this see a distinct object. So the challenge is how do we find
这个场景中的对象。我们希望能够做的就是找到一个地区
the object in this scene. All we want to be able to do is find a region
在这个场景中。我们将一个区域定义为一组连接的像素
within this scene. We’re going to define a region as a group of pixels that are connected
相互之间（也就是说，它们彼此相邻）都具有相同的颜色。
to each other (that is, they are next to each other) that have all got the same colour.
因此，如果我们能够做到这一点，如果对于这个场景中的所有白色像素，我们可以以某种方式
So if we could do that, if for all of the white pixels in this scene we could somehow
将它们聚集在一起，然后我们就能找到这个连贯的区域;这个对象。
clump them together, then we would be able to find this coherent region; this object.
然后我们就可以开始描述它的外观和内在的位置
And then we could begin the process of describing what it looks like and where it is within
图片。让我们付诸实践。我们将加载
the image. Let’s put this into practice. We will load
一个图像;鲨鱼的形象。将它放入工作区im，我们将显示它。这些
an image; the shark image. Put it into the workspace im, and we will display it. These
对我们来说都是非常熟悉的命令。我们将看一些像素值
are all very familiar commands to us by now. And we’ll have a look at some pixel values
在这里。黑色的值为0，白色的值为0
in here. The black ones have got a value of 0, and the white ones have got a value of
我们称之为二进制图像或逻辑图像。这些是带有值的黑色像素
1. We call this a binary image or a logical image. These are black pixels with a value
没有;可以被MATLAB视为假。这些可以由MATLAB考虑
of nought; could be considered by MATLAB as false. These could be considered by MATLAB
是的。该图像只有两个可能的像素值。
as true. This image has got only two possible pixel values.
现在我们要做的第一件事是制作所有像素的列表
Now the first thing that we’re going to do is to make a list of all of the pixels
在图像中，我们将使用MATLAB的内置“查找”来做到这一点
within the image, and we’re going to do that using MATLAB’s built-in ‘find’
功能。而我们要做的就是找到所有有价值的像素
function. And what we’re going to do is find all of the pixels who’ve got a value
大于0;这将是白色的。对于它找到的每个像素，每个元素
greater than 0; that will be the white ones. For every pixel that it finds, every element
它找到的矩阵，它将返回行坐标和列坐标
of the matrix that it finds, it will return the row coordinate and the column coordinate
进入那两个向量v和u。所以我们看到那些载体有7827
into those two vectors v and u. So we see that those vectors have got 7827
在它们中的行，所以这个图像中有7827个像素大于0.所以让我们
rows in them, so there are 7827 pixels in this image that are greater than 0. So let’s
看看这些坐标是什么。我要展示它们并且非常大
have a look at what these coordinates are. I’m going to display them and a very large
数字滚过去。那么让我们来看看其中的一些数字。它是什么
number of numbers rolls past. So let’s have a look at some of these numbers. What it’s
例如，说是坐标243处的像素，170是属于的白色像素
saying is, for instance, a pixel at coordinate 243, 170 is a white pixel that belongs to
鲨鱼。坐标244,169处的像素是属于鲨鱼的白色像素。
the shark. The pixel at coordinate 244, 169 is a white pixel that belongs to the shark.
我们有一个很长的白色像素坐标列表。我们可以用这些做什么？
We have a long list of the coordinates of the white pixels. What can we do with these?
我们能做的一件事就是找出u坐标的最小值，即
Well one thing we can do is find what is the smallest value of the u coordinate, that’s
该组白色像素中的最小u坐标，这将是最大的u坐标;
the smallest u coordinate in that set of white pixels, and this will be the largest u coordinate;
这是245.所以这是关于那套白色的最小u坐标的说法
it’s 245. So this is saying something about the smallest u coordinate of that set of white
像素，也是最大的。我们可以在垂直方向上做同样的事情;说最小的
pixels, and the largest. We can do the same in the vertical direction; say the smallest
垂直坐标和最大垂直坐标。所以这四个数字本质上是
vertical coordinate and the largest vertical coordinate. So these four numbers essentially
绑定那个鲨鱼形物体。所以让我们在场景上绘制一个方框，就是这样
bound that shark-shaped object. So let’s plot a box on the scene, and it’s
一个左上角为umin和vmin的盒子，右下角为umax
a box whose top left corner is u min and v min, and its bottom right corner is u max
和vmax，我们将它绘制成绿色。我们现在所做的就是放置什么
and v max, and we’ll plot it in the colour green. What we’ve done now is to place what
我们在这组白色像素周围调用一个边界框。
we call a bounding box around that set of white pixels.
所以我们现在可以对这组像素说些什么。我们能够说点什么
So we’re able now to say something about this set of pixels. We’re able to say something
关于这些像素在图像中的位置。我们可以做的另一件事就是说在哪里
about where these pixels are within the image. Another thing that we can do is to say where
是这组像素的中心。这样做的一个简单方法就是说中心
is the centre of this group of pixels. And a simple way of doing this is to say the centre
我们可以认为是最小和最大坐标的平均值。所以
we could think of as being the average of the minimum and maximum coordinates. So in
水平方向就是那个数字。在垂直方向上就是这样
the horizontal direction it’s that number. In the vertical direction it will be this
数。现在我们能做的就是为此绘制一个观点
number. Now what we can do is plot a point at that
使用plot_point函数的特定坐标：传递u坐标，v
particular coordinate using the plot_point function: pass in the u coordinate, the v
坐标...并且它期望列向量，我们将在该位置放置一个星号。
coordinate … and it expects the column vector, and we’ll put an asterisk at that location.
现在我们已经提出了一个观点，它在某些方面是该对象的中心。其实，
And now we have drawn a point, which in some ways is the centre of that object. Actually,
它是盒子的中心，大致是那组白色像素的中心。好
it’s the centre of the box and is roughly the centre of that set of white pixels. We’ll
很快就能做得更好。一种非常有用的技术
be able to do better than that shortly. A technique that’s going to be really helpful
对我们来说，这项工作就是计算出所谓的图像瞬间。时刻
for us in this endeavour is to compute what are called moments of the image. The moments
由这个等式给出，当前有两个参数，p和q。所以
are given by this equation, and there are two parameters to the moment, p and q. So
我们指的是图像的'p-qth时刻'。所以这一刻只是所有的总和
we refer to the ‘p-qth moment’ of an image. So the moment is simply the sum of all of
图像中的像素，该像素的u坐标与p的幂，即v坐标
the pixels in the image, of the u coordinate of that pixel to the power of p, the v coordinate
q的幂，乘以该特定坐标处的像素值。
to the power of q, multiplied by the value of the pixel at that particular coordinate.
目前我们正在处理二进制图像，因此像素值为0或1。
At the moment we’re dealing with binary images, so the pixel value is either 0 or 1.
一个特别有趣的时刻是
A particularly interesting moment is when
p等于q等于0.我们称之为图像的第0个时刻，因为p和q是
p equals q equals 0. We call this the zeroth moment of the image, and because p and q are
零，我们只是从总和中删除它们。0,0时刻只是像素的总和
zero, we simply remove them from the summation. The moment 0,0 is simply the sum of the pixel
值。现在，如果像素对于背景为0或对象为1，则为像素值
values. Now if pixels are either 0 for background or 1 for the object, then the sum pixel values
将成为该地区的一部分。它将是内部明亮像素的数量
is going to be the area of the region. It’s going to be the number of bright pixels within
我们刚才看到的鲨鱼。另一组非常有用的时刻是
the shark that we were just looking at. Another set of very useful moments are the
第一时间。这些是片刻1,0和片刻0,1。他们的方程是
first moments. And these are the moments 1,0 and the moment 0,1. And their equations are
这里显示。我们可以将这些视为u和v坐标的加权平均值，加权
shown here. We can think of these as weighted averages of the u and v coordinates, weighted
通过像素的颜色。所以，如果我们采取当下1,0的比例
by the colour of the pixels. So if we take the ratio of the moment 1,0 by the moment
0,0-这是第一个除以面积的时刻-这给了我们坐标
0,0—that’s the first moment divided by the area—this gives us the coordinates of
对象的质心，这非常有用。现在我们找到了几何中心
the centroid of the object, and this is really useful. Now we’ve found the geometric centre
这个鲨鱼形物体。我们开始了
of this shark-shaped object. We’re beginning to
能够描述它。让我们继续我们之前的会议。
be able to describe it. Let’s continue the session that we had earlier.
首先，我们将使用mpq函数计算场景的第0个时刻。我们会过去的
First, we’ll computer the zeroth moment of the scene using the mpq function. We’ll pass
在图像中：我们想要0，第0时刻。第零个时刻是区域或总数
in the image: we want the 0, zeroth moment. The zeroth moment is the area or the total
图像中的1个像素数。这是我们之前获得的价值。我们
number of 1 pixels in the image. And it’s the value that we obtained previously. We
计算时刻1,0，我们再次使用mpq函数;传递图像，
compute the moment 1,0, and we do that again using the mpq function; pass in the image,
因此，我们得到了相当大的数字。计算0,1...mpq的时刻
1 and 0. So we have this rather large number as a result. Compute the moment 0,1 … mpq
...图像...0和1.我们再次拥有一个非常大的数字。现在我们要做的就是计算
… image … 0 and 1. Again we have a very large number. Now what we’ll do is compute
该地区的质心。所以我们将使用的u坐标ucen等于m，1,0divide
the centroid of the region. So the u coordinate we’ll use, ucen, is equal to m,1,0 divided
由m，0,0。并且质心的v坐标是0,1除以第0个时刻，
by m,0,0. And the v coordinate of the centroid is the moment 0, 1 divided by the zeroth moment,
那是质心的垂直坐标。
and that is the vertical coordinate of the centroid.
让我们在图像上绘制;我们使用plot_point函数。传递你的u坐标
Let’s plot that on the image; we use the plot_point function. Pass in the u coordinate
和垂直坐标，将其转换为列向量，我们将指出这一点
and the vertical coordinate, turn it into a column vector, and we’ll indicate this
一个带圆形标记。在这里，我们有所有白色像素的质心
one with a circular marker. And here we have the centroid of all of the white pixels within
鲨鱼形物体。你可以看到它非常非常靠近中心
the shark-shaped object. You can see that it’s very, very close to the centre of the
框，这说明了这个鲨鱼对象相当对称的事实。
box, and that says something about the fact that this shark object is fairly symmetrical.